Hello Hello Everyone Friends This is the
best friend in Twenty20, after that the
popularity of health insurance has increased very rapidly,
after which people have not only
started purchasing policies for themselves
but today people like to take policies with a big risk cover, to
keep you updated at this critical time, we have uploaded videos
of almost all types of health insurance products
on our channel, despite
this, even today many people have
many kinds of false misconceptions about health insurance, due to which
today they are not able to change a good policy for themselves
and if they already have a
policy available, then they are
not able to utilize it properly
and in today's video we will
talk about 10 such most common and important mixes and will try our best to
give you clarification on all these friends, after which I am going to instill in you
that you will
definitely be able to purchase a good health insurance policy for yourself without any hesitation,
but for this it is necessary that
you end this video absolutely without any
script.  Look
friends, I am a certified financial planner
and my company Term Insurance
Marketing Private Limited provides
its health insurance services in almost all the states of India.
After watching this video, if you decide to
purchase any health insurance product from any
health insurance company's showroom,
then you must contact me
on my mobile number 98 08 and you can book an
online appointment with me. And now it's
time to start. So let's start with this,
Dharmveer Singh and your watching. This is for
your benefit.
[Music] The
first myth related to health insurance is
that young and healthy people do
not need health insurance.
Friends, this myth of yours has been
proved completely wrong by the second wave of Kovinash
and out of all the
patients found in 2001, five percent of them are those
whose age falls in the group of middle to 40 years.
Friends, today our
lifestyle or unhealthy food has weakened
our immunity system a lot.
Now, no matter what age we are
Why do you come in group? Today we need a
good and big risk cover health
insurance policy.
Another big myth related to health insurance is
that the group health insurance policy provided by our office or company is
sufficient for us. Friends, every
individual's requirements are different
and we need a health insurance policy
that is designed keeping
our individual requirements
in mind, whereas while designing a group health
insurance policy,
all the requirements of your company are taken into consideration instead of yours.
A group health insurance policy is
cheaper for you because this policy has
many types of exclusions and provisions, due to which
you are never able to fully utilize this policy when needed. The
biggest problem associated with this policy is that this policy
cannot remain with you for life.
Whenever you switch your job or leave your job,
this policy also
automatically stops and Idea also does
not have any such guideline that your
existing health insurance company will cancel your
policy like this.  Whether you can continue your individual policy or the
group health
insurance policy is
not portable, which means you
can't transfer it to another company.
Now, a major problem
arises: if you are
diagnosed with a disease during your lifetime, it becomes
very difficult for you to switch to
a new health insurance policy from another company,
or your existing health
insurance company also follows the
latest medical guidelines to offer you such an individual policy. The
third major concern related to health insurance is
that group
health insurance policies from banks are cheap and good.
Friends, it is absolutely true that
these policies are cheap, but it does
not mean that the policies are good. To
understand this in detail, it is
very important for you to understand that any
government bank or private bank is
basically a business institution; it is
not doing any social work for you.
Any transaction you make with these
banks generates profit for them,
and this is a part of that.  The premium for your
group health insurance policy is
kept low so that
customers purchase it through banks instead of directly from the health insurance company.
This does
n't mean that the product you get
from a health insurance company will be the same
product you get at a lower rate than from a bank. Rather,
health insurance companies
design group health insurance products specifically for banks. To
keep the product's price low, they
add various surcharges and exclusions, which can prevent
you from reaping the full benefits of the product if needed.
Furthermore,
customers with health insurance policies purchased from banks face constant service
issues, as
bank employees often offer no support during claims. It's
always difficult for individuals to deal directly with a health insurance company without the help of an agent. The
biggest problem with bank
policies is that they are
n't offered for life; they're offered for a
very short term, such as three
or five years. This is
because  Banks do not have their own
health insurance policy, rather
they enter into a type with a health insurance company
and it is that company's policy that the
agent sells to you. Now, as soon as this
type expires, your policy also gets discontinued.
For this, you can go and check in the bank. The
type of a bank can be from 2 years to 1
year, maximum 5 years. If you
go to any bank and ask whether your type has been
with this health insurance company for the last 10
years, then you will not find any bank
whose type has been with any company for the last 10 years.
Now, the problem in such a situation is that if during
this time you get diagnosed with any disease,
you have any medical condition
and this type expires, then after that
neither can you port this policy to any other company
nor is there any
such guideline of IRDA that your existing
bank policy can be converted into such an individual policy
because group
policy is a group product, it gets discontinued, at that
time if you apply for a policy from the existing company also, then
friends  Medical guidelines will be applicable
and if you are already diagnosed
with any medical condition, then neither the
existing company will provide you insurance
nor any other insurance company is going to give you
any kind of risk cover. If we
talk about the fourth Amit, then many people
believe that to purchase any health
insurance product,
you need to get a pre-medical screening done,
which friends, is not a mandatory pre-medical
screen,
rather it is mandatory that your health
insurance company should have information about your health condition.
If you are
diagnosed with any existing disease, then
your company should know about it. If
you have taken any major treatment, then your
company should be aware about it.
To collect this information, the
company has two ways, one is through
pre-medical screening
and the second option is at most good faith
and today many companies follow at most good faith, a
very good example of this is
Manipal Signal's product, which you will see on our channel.  There
is a product in it for up
to sixty-five years, if you take it
then without any medical test your policy
is accepted on the basis of most good faith and if your age is more than 160 or
7085 years in anything, if you
want to purchase the product then there
is a red carpet policy of this and health, the
complete details of this policy have been
given to you through a video on our channel, so
friends there are many such companies which
accept your policy on the basis of most good faith
and in most interest you simply have to
mention your health condition score on your proposal form and on that basis
your proposal is accepted,
related to health insurance, then it is said in it that for making a
claim in health insurance policies, it is mandatory to have hospitalization of at least two to four years
or more,
so friends this
is absolutely wrong because mandatory to 4 is not today's
hospitalization, rather the mandatory thing is that
for any critical medical condition you  If you are hospitalized, the
health insurance company gives you a claim for it. A
very good example of this is
that in all the videos available on our channel,
in all the products related to health insurance,
day care treatment and infection
treatment facilities have been provided. So,
in day care, basically if you are admitted for less than 24 hours,
in domiciliary treatment, if you want to get treatment from your home,
in infection hospitalization, when
you are admitted in the hospital for more than 24 hours, then
you can plan for all three conditions through your health insurance policy.
Apart from this, one of the six conditions
related to health insurance is that
since maternity is not a disease, it
cannot be covered under a health insurance policy. Friends, it is a fact
that today there are products available in the market
which cover your maternity condition after only nine months. A
very good example of this is that generally you get the
complete details of this product on our channel. I will
also put its meaning in the description,
you can see it from there.
And there are many such products available in the market
which easily cover maternity after 2 years, 3 years or 4 years of
ex-servicemanship,
so today maternity health insurance
policy is not a problem in this and the
Seventh Maths health insurance policy
regarding this is that after purchasing the health insurance policy, one can
avail the benefits of the policy immediately and believing this,
many people purchase health insurance policy for major surgery
and
immediately apply for the claim related to their surgery
and their balance is
rejected friends, this happens
because there are
three types of standard exclusions in any policy
like 30 days waiting period,
if you change any health insurance product then there is a
waiting period of 30 days for any type of hospitalization, yes accidental cases are
covered only by Devan,
apart from this, there is a 2 year exclusion for some 15 degrees, only
after that
you can get treatment for 19 and  If you have
a favourite song
which you have
mentioned in your proposal form during At Most Good Feet or the
company has diagnosed it in the free medical screening at the
time of giving you the policy, then
such disease is considered among all pre-existing
diseases and it completely
depends on the company. Some companies cover it after one year,
some companies after two, three or four years. The
8th minute related to health insurance policy is
that in this, drunkards and drinkers
cannot change the policy, so friends, this is
not at all like that.
You have full eligibility for any health insurance product. The
only thing is that
because you drink on this occasion,
your health can deteriorate quickly and more.
For this, you have to pay premium additionally
because health insurance
companies put extra loading for these smoked drinks in their product. The ninth thing in
health insurance was that
my friend is my event. Friends,
today many such
people purchase policies from their friends, friends of friends, from their
relatives, who  This
is absolutely wrong and
can lead to huge losses. Look,
while purchasing an insurance product, it is
very important to look at your agent. The first thing
you need to do is to see whether
your agent is an insurance professional, how much
experience he has in the insurance industry, whether he is aware of
all the products of health insurance companies
or not, and whether your
agent will be able to help you at the time of claim. If
your agent has all these qualities, then it does
not matter whether he
is your relative or friend or a
stranger. If a good professional
advises you and he has been in this profession for a
long time, then he will definitely be able to
help you in your problem. But if
your relative or your friend is
not able to suggest a good policy or is not able to
help you in your problem, then
this can be very loss-making for you. It is
better that you do
not change the policy at least you will
definitely be able to share your premium. And last but not least,
see the Smith of Health Insurance. People believe that if we do
not pay the premium of the health insurance policy on due date, then our policy will be permanently cancelled.  It gets
terminated whereas it is not so.
In any health insurance product,
you are given a grace period of 30 days
and if any claim comes in this 30 day grace period then
no one will get it now
but in this 30 day grace period you get the
opportunity that you
can revive your policy tomorrow so friends these were the
timings of health insurance I hope
you must have liked the video friends
if after watching this video you are making up your mind to
purchase any health insurance policy
then you must contact me on
my mobile number
9810 244 118 and friends if you
like the video then do like the video and
share it with your friends as much as possible
and if you are a new viewer of our channel
then do subscribe to the channel and press the
bell icon attached to it, this will
benefit you that
you will keep getting notifications of all our important videos
regularly so that's all for today, I will meet
you in the next video
with some more benefits for you, thank you